#### DATA SCIENTIST · BUSINESS ANALYST

51, USJ 11/1G, 47620 Subang Jaya, Selangor, Malaysia

□ (+60) 16-938-7109 | ■ tancm96@gmail.com | ★ lucastancm96.github.io | □ lucastancm96 | □ cheeming-tan

## **Summary** \_

A recent postgraduate student of MSc Business Analytics from The University of Manchester. Ex-performance specialist experience in managing search and display ads with track records of generating 4,000 leads and 90,000 clicks for all campaigns. Key expertises include statistical modelling, operational research, and digital marketing. Well-equipped with machine learning knowledge, especially tree-based algorithm and capable in implementing data mining processes, both independently or as a member of a cross functional team.

## **Education**

### The University of Manchester

Manchester, UK

MSc Business Analytics: Operational Research and Risk Analysis

Sept 2019 - Sept 2020

• Predicted First Class Honours

#### **Sheffield Hallam University**

Sheffield, UK

BSc (Hons) Marketing Management

May 2016 - May 2018

• First Class Honours

## **Tunku Abdul Rahman University College**

Kuala Lumpur, MY

BBus (Hons) Marketing

May 2014 - May 2018

- BB05 (HONS) MARKETIN
- CGFA 3.19
- · Receiver of full TARUC Merit Scholarships awarded to 10As achiever in Malaysian Certificate of Education (SPM)

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

## **Gapture Malaysia Sdn Bhd**

Kuala Lumpur, MY

PERFORMANCE SPECIALIST

Jan 2019 - Aug 2019

- Implemented Google and Facebook ads campaign with a total budget of RM300,000, generating over 4,000 leads and 90,000 clicks for all campaigns.
- Integrated analytics tools and successfully tracked over 1,000 events and increased conversion rate by 5%.
- · Prepared monthly report using data mining and data visualization software to build effective feedback system and relationships with clients.
- · Created and managed Facebook contents for a global oil & gas company, gaining over 500 organic page likes within 6 months.

#### The Inside Scoop Sdn Bhd

Kuala Lumpur, MY

MARKETING INTERN

Feb 2018 - May 2018

- Planned and executed 4 high-yielding marketing campaigns, e.g. generated more than 50 cake orders with an estimated total revenue of RM6,000 for Mother's Day campaign.
- Negotiated with local and China suppliers and helped company saved 37% of buying cost.
- Liaised with accounting department to resolve international transaction issues.

AirAsia Bhd Sepang, MY

Marketing Intern

May 2016 - Jun 2016

- · Managed weekly promotional contents on AirAsia's website and email for Australia and New Zealand market.
- Conducted a rigorous competitor analysis on 5 different airlines along with other market researches to explore new market opportunities in Sharjah and Medina.

# Projects\_\_\_\_\_

## Dissertation: Evaluating Global Vaccine Attitudes Using Data Mining Approach

Manchester, UK

- An in-depth study on global vaccine attitudes and coverage aimed to assist policymakers in devising effective immunization scheme to cope with COVID-19
- The research was performed through a robust data mining approach that involves data preprocessing, exploratory data analysis, clustering analysis, and predictive modeling.
- · Machine learning algorithms implemented comprised of k-means, decision tree, random forest, and gradient boosting.
- Tools and packages used include Python, R, Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, MICE, Seaborn, Matplotlib, ggplot2, Tableau, and etc.

CHEEMING TAN · RÉSUMÉ

### **Sales Forecast for Drug Store**

Manchester, UK

- Forecasted sales for a large drug store chain in Europe from a dataset consisting of 1M+ sales records and other data such as promotion through time series analysis and random forest.
- Data preprocessing was conducted on R using MICE package.
- Exploratory data analysis and predictive modelling were performed through Python with Scikit-Learn, Facebook Prophet, Seaborn, and etc.

### Simulation Modelling for Massachusetts General Hospital's PATA

Manchester, UK

 Simulated patient in-and-out flows with the application of Queuing Theory and proposed solution to resolve bottleneck issues in the hospital through SIMUL8.

#### Performance & Efficiency Analysis for Fashion Retailer's Suppliers

Manchester, UK

- Ranked the best supplier according to their attributes through multiple-criteria decision analysis, multiple objective linear programming, and data envelopment analysis.
- Performed analysis using IDS and Excel Solver.

#### **Travelling Santa Problem**

Manchester, UK

- Optimized Santa's delivery route by minimizing reindeer weariness using random search and simulated annealing algorithms that were applied
  on 100K dataset consisting of gifts information such as latitude and longitude.
- Conducted on Python using packages including Scikit-learn, SciPy, Matploblib, Seaborn, and etc.

## **Jelly Bean Sales Regression Analysis**

Manchester, UK

- · Built a marketing mix model via linear regression model in R to find the association between jelly bean sales and promotion mix.
- Implemented k-fold cross validation and assumption tests to enhance model robustness.

#### **Optimization of Student-Project Allocation**

Manchester, UK

• Optimize the allocation of student to research supervisor through the application of linear programming technique including objective and constraints formulation, and solve the problem using Excel Solver.

# **Extracurricular Activity**

Marketing Society Kuala Lumpur, MY

Business Director Dec 2017 - Mac 2018

Led a team of 11 in organizing a beauty expo which successfully acquired 50 vendors, attracted over 9,000 walk-ins, and raised above RM16,000 for both university's student centre and Marketing Society.

#### **Waitrose Employability Event**

Sheffield, UK

TEAM LEAD

Jul 2017

• Collaborated with 2 members to perform field research and developed an effective Malaysian market expansion strategy for Sheffield Waitrose's management team.

#### **Student Representative Council**

Kuala Lumpur, MY

WELFARE OFFICER

Jun 2016 - May 2017

• Initiated 5 projects with the welfare teams and helped the university implement new policy and system that brought positive impacts to the students' welfare in overall aspects.

## **Skills & Tools**

**Programming** Python, R, SQL, SAS, VBA

Machine LearningPandas, Numpy, Scikit-Learn, StatsmodelsVisualizationTableau, Matplotlib, Seaborn, ggplot2, Plotly

Web HTML, CSS, WordPress, Beautiful Soup, Selenium, Requests

Other GitHub, Facebook Business Manager, Google Ads, Google Analytics, Excel Solver, SIMUL8, IDS

**Languages** English, Malay, Mandarin, Cantonese

# **Achievements**

2016TARUC President's List AwardKuala Lumpur, MY2016TARUC Dean's List AwardKuala Lumpur, MY2016TARUC Book Prize AwardKuala Lumpur, MY2016iStar-Internship Program FinalistKuala Lumpur, MY

CHEEMING TAN · RÉSUMÉ